So recently,
مؤخراً،
some white guys and some black women
تبادل بعض الشباب البيض والنساء السود
swapped Twitter avatars, or pictures online.
شعارات تويتر أو صورًا عبر الإنترنت.
They didn't change their content,
ولم يغيروا محتوياتها،
they kept tweeting the same as usual,
وظلوا يغردون بنفس الطريقة كالعادة،
but suddenly, the white guys noticed
لكن فجأة، لاحظ الشباب البيض
they were getting called the n-word all the time
أنهم أصبحوا ينادون بالزنوج طوال الوقت
and they were getting the worst kind of online abuse,
وأنهم أصبحوا يتلقون أفظع أنواع الإساءة عبر الإنترنت،
whereas the black women all of a sudden
بينما لاحظت النساء السود فجأة
noticed things got a lot more pleasant for them.
أن الأمور أصبحت لطيفة جدا معهن.
Now, if you're my five-year-old,
الآن، إذا كان عمرك خمس سنوات،
your Internet consists mostly of puppies and fairies
فستغلب على محتوياتك الإلكترونية صور الجِراء والجنيات
and occasionally fairies riding puppies.
والجنيات تمتطي الجِراء أحيانا.
That's a thing. Google it.
هذا هو الواقع. ابحث عن ذلك في جوجل.
But the rest of us know that the Internet
لكن بقيتنا يعرف أن الإنترنت
can be a really ugly place.
يمكن أن تكون مكانا قبيحا حقا.
I'm not talking about the kind of colorful debates
أنا لا أتحدث عن المناقشات متعددة الألوان
that I think are healthy for our democracy.
التي أعتقد أنها صحية لديموقراطيتنا.
I'm talking about nasty personal attacks.
أنا أتحدث عن الهجمات الشخصية البغيضة.
Maybe it's happened to you, but it's at least
ربما حدث لك ذلك، لكن على الأقل
twice as likely to happen, and be worse,
احتمال حدوث ذلك يبلغ الضعف، أو أسوأ،
if you're a woman, a person of color, or gay,
إذا كنت امرأة، أو من الملونين، أو شاذًا،
or more than one at the same time.
أو أكثر من واحد في نفس الوقت.
In fact, just as I was writing this talk,
في الحقيقة، وبينما كنت أكتب هذه المحادثة،
I found a Twitter account called @SallyKohnSucks.
وجدت حسابا على تويتر باسم SallyKohnSucks@.
The bio says that I'm a
تقول السيرة الذاتية أنني
"man-hater and a bull dyke and the only thing I've ever accomplished with my career
"كارهة للرجال وسحاقية وأن الشيء الوحيد الذي حققته في حياتي المهنية
is spreading my perverse sexuality."
هو نشر انحرافي الجنسي."
Which, incidentally, is only a third correct.
التي، بالمناسبة، ثلثها فقط صحيح.
I mean, lies! (Laughter)
أقصد، أكاذيب! (ضحك)
But seriously, we all say we hate this crap.
لكن جديا، نقول جميعًا أننا نكره هذا الهراء.
The question is whether you're willing to make
السؤال هو ما إذا كنتم مستعدين لتقديم
a personal sacrifice to change it.
تضحيات شخصية لتغيير ذلك.
I don't mean giving up the Internet.
أنا لا أقصد ترك الإنترنت.
I mean changing the way you click,
بل أقصد تغيير طريقة تصفحنا لها،
because clicking is a public act.
لأن التصفح عمل عام.
It's no longer the case
لم يعد الأمر مجرد
that a few powerful elites control all the media
تحكم نخب قوية قليلة في جميع وسائل الإعلام
and the rest of us are just passive receivers.
وبقيتنا مجرد مستقبلين سلبيين.
Increasingly, we're all the media.
في الحقيقة أننا جميعا نصنع الإعلام.
I used to think, oh, okay, I get dressed up,
اعتدت على الاعتقاد، أوه، حسنا، أن ألبس،
I put on a lot of makeup,
وأضع الكثير من الماكياج،
I go on television, I talk about the news.
وأظهر على التلفزيون، وأتحدث عن الأخبار.
That is a public act of making media.
هذا عمل عام لصناعة الإعلام.
And then I go home and I browse the web
ثم أعود إلى المنزل وأتصفح الإنترنت
and I'm reading Twitter,
وأقرأ تغريدات تويتر،
and that's a private act of consuming media.
وأعتبر ذلك شأنًا خاصًا للاستهلاك الإعلامي.
I mean, of course it is. I'm in my pajamas.
أنا أقصد، بالطبع هو كذلك. أن أكون في بيجامتي.
Wrong.
خطأ.
Everything we blog, everything we Tweet,
فأي تدوينة ندونها، وكل تغريدة على تويتر،
and everything we click
وكل رابط نتصفحه
is a public act of making media.
يُعد عملًا عامًا لصناعة الإعلام.
We are the new editors.
نحن هم المحررون الجدد.
We decide what gets attention
نحن من يقرر ما يستحوذ على الانتباه
based on what we give our attention to.
بناء على ما نهتم به.
That's how the media works now.
هكذا يعمل الإعلام الآن.
There's all these hidden algorithms that decide
فجميع هذه الخوارزميات الخفية التي تحدد
what you see more of and what we all see more of
أن ما تراه أكثر و ما نراه أكثر من غيره
based on what you click on,
على أساس الروابط التي تتصفحها،
and that in turn shapes our whole culture.
وهذا بدوره يشكل ثقافتنا بأسرها.
Over three out of five Americans think we have
ثلاثة أو أكثر من كل خمسة أمريكيين
a major incivility problem in our country right now,
يعتقدون أننا نعاني حاليًا من مشكلة وقاحة كبرى في دولتنا،
but I'm going to guess that at least three out of five
لكني أعتقد أن ثلاثة من بين خمسة
Americans are clicking on the same insult-oriented,
أمريكيين على الأقل يشاهدون نفس المواقع
rumor-mongering trash that feeds
الكريهة التي تروج للشائعات وتغذي
the nastiest impulses in our society.
أقذر الرغبات في مجتمعنا.
In an increasingly noisy media landscape,
في بيئة إعلامية صاخبة بشكل متزايد،
the incentive is to make more noise to be heard,
مبدأ قم بعمل مزيد من الصخب لتكون مسموعًا
and that tyranny of the loud
وأن الغلبة للصوت الأعلى
encourages the tyranny of the nasty.
يشجع على طغيان البذائة.
It does not have to be that way.
يجب ألا يكون الأمر على هذا النحو .
It does not.
على الإطلاق.
We can change the incentive.
نستطيع أن نغيير المبدأ.
For starters, there are two things we can all do.
للبدء، هناك شيئان يمكنا فعلهما
First, don't just stand by the sidelines when you see someone getting hurt.
أولًا، لا تكن مجرد مشاهد عندما ترى شخصًا يتأذى.
If someone is being abused online, do something.
افعل شيئًا إذا رأيت شخصًا تُساء معاملته عبر الإنترنت.
Be a hero. This is your chance.
كن بطلًا. هذه فرصتك.
Speak up. Speak out. Be a good person.
تكلم. عبر. كن شخصًا طيبًا.
Drown out the negative with the positive.
احجب السلبي بالإيجابي.
And second, we've got to stop clicking
ثانيًا، يجب أن نتوقف عن تصفح
on the lowest-common-denominator, bottom-feeding
حثالة المحتويات عديمة الجدوى
linkbait.
للروابط المثيرة.
If you don't like the 24/7 all Kardashian
إذا لم تكن تحب برامج كارديشان 24/7
all the time programming,
التي تحاصرنا على مدار الساعة،
you've got to stop clicking on the stories
يجب أن تتوقف عن تصفح القصص
about Kim Kardashian's sideboob.
المتعلقة بثدي كيم كارديشان نصف العاري.
I know you do it. (Applause)
أعلم أنكم تفعلون ذلك. (تصفيق)
You too, apparently.
أنت أيضًا، على ما يبدو.
I mean, really, same example:
أعني، حقًا، نفس المثال:
if you don't like politicians calling each other names,
إن لم يرقك منظر السياسيين وهم يتبادلون الشتائم،
stop clicking on the stories
توقف عن تصفح القصص
about what one guy in one party called the other guy in the other party.
التي تتداول الشتائم التي وجهها أحد أعضاء حزب ما لشخص في حزب آخر.
Clicking on a train wreck just pours gasoline on it.
مجرد تصفح البرامج الواقعية يصب عليها الغاز.
It makes it worse, the fire spreads.
ويجعل الأمر أسوأ، وينشر النار أكثر.
Our whole culture gets burned.
ثقافتنا بأسرها تحترق.
If what gets the most clicks wins,
فإذا كانت المواقع الأكثر تصفحًا تفوز،
then we have to start shaping the world we want
فحينئذ يجب علينا البدء في تشكيل العالم الذي نريده
with our clicks,
من خلال تصفحنا،
because clicking is a public act.
لأن التصفح عمل عام.
So click responsibly. Thank you.
لذلك تصفح بمسؤولية. شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)